{
    "id": "1cd91a83e8c14fec937294bae6942951",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The party invitations ………………………. out.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect tense to simply give news of recent events.",
            "answers": [
                "have sent",
                "have been sent",
                "are sending"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2ba43f827d534a39810cb14ccd6643d5"
        },
        {
            "question": "The invention of the space rocket …………………….. many years.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "took",
                "has taken",
                "were taken"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c7d0db7bd2f24495b25608af80b1b6dd"
        },
        {
            "question": "Alexander Graham Bell ……………………… the telephone.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "was invented",
                "has invented",
                "invented"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a1ed0a2a29ea4a718a729a9ae839eb72"
        },
        {
            "question": "Saint Patrick ……………………….. Christianity to the Irish.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "introduced",
                "was introduced",
                "has introduced"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "70282a408b894fc8928d55611a3dec74"
        },
        {
            "question": "Fairy tales ………………………….. most children.",
            "description": "We use the present simple to talk about facts, general truths and habits.",
            "answers": [
                "are intriguing",
                "intrigue",
                "are intrigued"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ca75f79d83494147b3082164fce6b327"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………….. to 90 days in jail.",
            "description": "We need a passive verb here because the subject is not the doer of the action.",
            "answers": [
                "sentenced",
                "was sentenced",
                "has sentenced"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "34e05646f9084849a4f9c13fbcfa4949"
        },
        {
            "question": "She …………………………. with joy upon the birth of her grandchild.",
            "description": "We need a passive verb here because the subject is not the doer of the action. Instead, something happened to the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "filled",
                "was filled",
                "was filling"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6baa9322b1b64084a1a007fe3ddbbf0a"
        },
        {
            "question": "How did you know I ……………………….. be there?",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we will need a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "shall"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0a926ceec361476484b0656d5ca494ff"
        },
        {
            "question": "He wanted to visit the land his father ……………………… from.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we will need a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "came",
                "come",
                "has come"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1bc8f127a45c4f81b0b6fad1682efb8f"
        },
        {
            "question": "Lately I ………………………… making my own clothes.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to talk about recent events. ",
            "answers": [
                "started",
                "have started",
                "had started"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c8030c6f6ed54b13a95a81e39fef68be"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. the packages on the table.",
            "description": "To lay something is to place it somewhere.",
            "answers": [
                "Lay",
                "Lie"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9259160786824169be1ae3d0b0ae0a40"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which route ................................. I take to Denver?",
            "description": "The simple present is the tense used to ask for or give directions. ",
            "answers": [
                "do",
                "have",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "36a0b229077b4f6587e3d913b204ce39"
        }
    ]
}